<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Language Learning on Jonathan`s Blog</title>
    <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/categories/language-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Language Learning on Jonathan`s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 13:26:49 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jonathanwayy.xyz/categories/language-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CATTI Vocabulary Notes</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2021/catti-vocab-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 13:26:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2021/catti-vocab-notes/</guid>
      <description>Eng Chi Notes full of prunes 愚蠢透顶的；完全错误的；浮夸的；活跃的；兴高采烈的；精力充沛的 prunes and prisms （言行的）装腔作势，矫揉造作 grate on sb. 把某人惹火了 a tenuous hope 一线希望</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>34 Posh English Words</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/eng2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 19:58:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/eng2/</guid>
      <description>marvellous great, wonderful splendid excellent, very good sensational very good, excellent, wonderful spiffing very good(often used to mock or emulate posh people) stupendous extremely large, extremely impressive ravishing extremely beautiful dashing attractive, confident and elegent(often used to describe a man) joyous very happy; causing people to be happy glorious very beautiful and impressive or extremely enjoyable eclectic not following one style or using a wide variety [She has very eclectic taste in music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English Vocab Notes</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/eng1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 23:32:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/eng1/</guid>
      <description>Word Definition     prudent a. careful and sensible; marked by sound judgment   eradicate To eradicate something means to get rid of it completely.   lurk If someone lurks somewhere, they wait there secretly so that they cannot be seen, usually because they intend to do something bad.   posh elegant and fashionable   dough a flour mixture stiff enough to knead or roll; informal terms for money   crisps a thin crisp slice of potato fried in deep fat   mischievous naughtily or annoyingly playful   esbresso strong black coffee brewed by forcing hot water under pressure through finely ground coffee beans   stanch stop the flow of a liquid   efficacy n.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
