<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on Jonathan`s Blog</title>
    <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/tags/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on Jonathan`s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 04:55:03 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jonathanwayy.xyz/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BLWL[34] Vim 设置背景透明</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/blwl34/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 04:55:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/blwl34/</guid>
      <description>Vim 通过 colorscheme 设置了主题后，通常背景会变成实色，想要让 Vim 的背景色跟随终端的透明度配置，在 .vimrc 文件中加入如下一行即可： hi Normal ctermfg=252 ctermbg=none</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>压缩图表空间以调整 Latex 版面</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/latex_vspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 23:51:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/latex_vspace/</guid>
      <description>很多会议论文都有特定的模板格式，并且在篇幅上有所限制，为了尽可能地多写一点内容，可以考虑在图像、表格、公式中利用 \vspace{} 来压缩垂直距离。 例如： \begin{figure*}[t] \vspace{-1.0cm}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>炼丹杂记 -- &#39; xsrf&#39; argument missing from POST 解决方法</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/ldp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 12:47:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/ldp1/</guid>
      <description>问题描述 Jupyter Notebook 保存时出现 ‘_xsrf’ argument missing from POST 错误，保存失败。 解决方法 刷新 Jupyter Notebook 的 home 界面即可，简单粗暴，亲测有效。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BLWL[33] Manjaro Linux 下 Docker 的安装与使用</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/blwl33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 22:17:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/blwl33/</guid>
      <description>背景知识 Docker 是一个开源的应用容器引擎，基于 Go 语言并遵从 Apache 2.0 协议开源。 Docker 可以让开发者打包他们的应用以及依赖包到一个轻量级、可移植的容器中，然后发</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KMP 算法笔记 - Next、Nextval数组求法、失配回退及复杂度</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/kmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 16:55:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/kmp/</guid>
      <description>Next 数组求法 1. 字符串 str 元素下标从 1 开始； 2. 令 Next[1] = 0，Next[2] = 1； 3. 令 i = 3，判断 str[i-1] 与 str[Next[i-1]] 是否相等； 3.1 若相等，则 Next[i] = Next[i-1] + 1； 3.2 若不相等，则</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Kali学习笔记1] Kali Linux渗透测试介绍</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/kali1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 15:43:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/kali1/</guid>
      <description>安全问题的根源 优点：分工明确，工作效率高。 缺点：从业人员对系统没有整体的认识，对安全认识较为片面。 最大威胁是人，人都会犯错，安全问题不能10</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>考研数学复习杂笔记 -- 线性代数</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/math-la/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 21:46:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/math-la/</guid>
      <description>要证明行列式为零，除了直接计算验证外，可以主动构造相应的其次线性方程组，证明其有非零解(全书P389)；</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>考研数学复习杂笔记 -- 多元函数积分学</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/math-dj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 17:12:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/math-dj/</guid>
      <description>三重积分交换积分次序可采用两两交换的策略</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>考研英语复习笔记</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/eng-ky1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 15:27:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/eng-ky1/</guid>
      <description>1 Lord Irvine said he ____ with a committee report this year&amp;hellip;. (sided / agreed) sided with 一般接人，故此处选择 agreed 2 lay down 1.中断；辞职；放弃 2.规定；制订（条例或规则） 3 be in safe hands (with sb.) 在可靠的人手中；</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[12] - Configuration Management</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 16:43:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes12/</guid>
      <description>Because software changes frequently, systems, can be thought of as a set of versions, each of which has to be maintained and managed. Configuration management (CM) is concerned with the policies, processes and tools for managing changing software systems. CM Activities Change management Keeping track of requests for changes to the software from customers and developers, working out the costs and impact of changes, and deciding the changes should be</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[11] - Quality Management</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 16:19:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes11/</guid>
      <description>Concerned with ensuring that the required level of quality is achieved in a software product. Three principal concerns: At the organizational level, quality management is concerned with establishing a framework of organizational processes and standards that will lead to high-quality software. At the project level, quality management involves the application of specific quality processes and checking that these planned processes have been followed. At the project level, quality management is</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[10] - Project Planning</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 13:08:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes10/</guid>
      <description>Project planning involves breaking down the work into parts and assign these to project team members, anticipate problems that might arise and prepare tentative solutions to those problems. The aim of planning at this stage is to provide information that will be used in setting a price for the system to customers. Plan sections Introduction Project organization Risk analysis Hardware and software resource requirements Work breakdown Project schedule Monitoring and</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[9] - Project Management</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 11:30:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes9/</guid>
      <description>Concerned with activities involved in ensuring that software is delivered on time and on schedule and in accordance with the requirements of the organisations developing and procuring the software. Success Criteria Deliver the software to the customer at the agreed time. Keep overall costs within budget. Deliver software that meets the customer’s expectations. Maintain a happy and well-functioning development team. Management</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[8] - Software Evolution</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 19:30:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes8/</guid>
      <description>A key problem for all organizations is implementing and managing change to their existing software systems. The software evolution process Change implementation Program Evolution Dynamics Program evolution dynamics is the study of the processes of system change. After several major empirical studies, Lehman and Belady proposed that there were a number of ‘laws’ which applied to all systems as they evolved. There are sensible observations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[7] - Software Testing</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 13:43:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes7/</guid>
      <description>Program Testing Goals To demonstrate to the developer and the customer that the software meets its requirements. (leads to validation testing) To discover situations in which the behavior of the software is incorrect, undesirable or does not conform to its specification. (leads to defect testing) Testing can only show the presence of errors in a program. It cannot demonstrate that there are no remaining faults. Verification vs Validation Verification &amp;ldquo;Are</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[6] - Design And Implementation</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 19:09:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes6/</guid>
      <description>Software design and implementation activities are invariably inter-leaved. An Object-oriented Design Process Object-oriented design processes involve developing a number of different system models. They require a lot of effort for development and maintenance of these models and, for small systems, this may not be cost-effective. However, for large systems developed by different groups design models are an important communication mechanism. Common activities Define the context and modes of use of</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[5] - Architectural Design</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 13:47:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes5/</guid>
      <description>The design process for identifying the sub-systems making up a system and the framework for sub-system control and communication is architectural design, which is an early stage of the system design process. The output of this design process is a description of the software architecture. It represents the link between specification and design processes and is often carried out in parallel with some specification activities. Each architectural model only shows</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[4] - System Modeling</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 09:53:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes4/</guid>
      <description>System modeling is the process of developing abstract models of a system, with each model presenting a different view or perspective of that system. System modeling helps the analyst to understand the functionality of the system and models are used to communicate with customers. Unified Modeling Language (UML) The UML is the standard language for visualizing, specifying, constructing, and documenting the artifacts of a software-intensive system. It can be used</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[3] - Requirements Engineering</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 17:24:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes3/</guid>
      <description>Types Of Requirement User requirements: Statements in natural language plus diagrams of the services the system provides and its operational constraints. Written for customers. System requirements: A structured document setting out detailed descriptions of the system’s functions, services and operational constraints. Defines what should be implemented so may be part of a contract between client and contractor. Functional And Non-functional Requirements Functional requirements</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[2] - Agile Software Development</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 17:18:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes2/</guid>
      <description>Agile Methods Features Focus on the code rather than the design. Are based on an iterative approach to software development. Are intended to deliver working software quickly and evolve this quickly to meet changing requirements. The aim of agile methods is to reduce overheads in the software process (e.g. by limiting documentation) and to be able to respond quickly to changing requirements without excessive rework. The principles of agile methods</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>软件工程复习笔记[1] - Software Process</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 14:31:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/se-notes1/</guid>
      <description>Software Process Software processes are the activities involved in producing a software system. General Software process models: The waterfall model, Incremental development, Reuse-oriented software engineering. Waterfall model phases: Requirements analysis and definition, System and software design, Implementation and unit testing, Integration and system testing, Operation and maintenance. The main drawback of the waterfall model: the difficulty of accommodating change after the process is underway. (In principle, a phase has to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numpy散记 -- allclose函数的使用</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/numpy-allclose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:09:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/numpy-allclose/</guid>
      <description>函数原型 numpy.allclose(a, b, rtol=1e-05, atol=1e-08, equal_nan=False) 参数 a, b：用于比较的两个输入数组 rtol：float型，相对容忍系数（relative tolerance parameter） atol：fl</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numpy散记 -- clip函数的使用</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/numpy-clip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 12:54:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/numpy-clip/</guid>
      <description>函数原型 numpy.clip(a, a_min, a_max, out=None, **kwargs) 参数 a：数组 a_max：数组元素最大值 a_min：数组元素最小值 功能 np.clip()函数用于将数组元素的值保持在给定区间</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>考研数学复习杂笔记 -- 多元函数微分学</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/math-dw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 16:19:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/math-dw/</guid>
      <description>多元函数可导推不出连续与可微：多元的可导是指一阶偏导数存在，而偏导数是用一元函数极限定义的，只与点\((x_{0}, y_{0})\)邻域内过</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>考研数学复习杂笔记 -- 向量代数与空间解析几何</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/math-vk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:53:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/math-vk/</guid>
      <description>混合积为零等价于三向量共面 求\(\vec{a}\)和\(\vec{b}\)的对角线向量可以求\(\vec{a}^{o}+\vec{b}^{o</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BLWL[27] Shell 杂记</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/blwl27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 10:06:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/blwl27/</guid>
      <description>cd - 回到前一个工作路径 若在输入命令时中途改变了主意，可以按下** Alt-#* *在行首添加 # 以注释该命令并回车执行（相当于依次按下 **Ctrl-A, #, Enter**）。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BLWL[26] Axel Command Tips</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/blwl26/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:00:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/blwl26/</guid>
      <description>axel 是 Linux 下一个不错的 HTTP/ftp 高速下载工具。 axel 支持多线程下载、断点续传，且可以从多个地址或者从一个地址的多个连接来下载同一个文件。 下载过程中断可以再执</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>炼丹杂记 -- 饱和激活函数</title>
      <link>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/dl-notes1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 09:07:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jonathanwayy.xyz/2020/dl-notes1/</guid>
      <description>饱和激活函数 当自变量趋于正无穷时，若激活函数的导数趋于0,则称之为右饱和。 当自变量趋于负无穷时，若激活函数的导数趋于0,则称之为左饱和。 若一</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
